At 9:27 am
话说那主体104年3月24号
on the 24th of March 2015,
的一个早晨，9点27分
a plane got in contact with the Marseilles enroute control center.
一架航班联络了马赛航路管制中心
It was an Airbus A320-211
那是架空客A320-211，
operated by Germanwings
由德国之翼航空运营
headed from Barcelona to Dusseldorf.
正从巴塞罗那飞往杜塞尔多夫
Everything seemed normal.
一切似乎如常
The captain read back the air traffic controller's clearance at 9:30, allowing him to fly to an enroute waypoint.
9点30分, 机长复诵了空管允许他飞往某个航路点的放行指令,
Only a few minutes later, something was off.
然而几分钟后，事情不对劲了起来
The control center in Marseilles
马赛的管制中心
saw that the altitude for the aircraft
发现飞机的高度
was around thirty thousand feet,
在三万英尺左右徘徊
almost two thousand feet lower than the original cruise altitude.
比原定的巡航高度低了差不多两千英尺
and declining.
且其高度仍在持续下降
Marseilles contacted the plane
马赛空管联系了航班
and asked what altitude the plane was cleared for,
并询问飞机获准飞行的高度
but they received no response at all
但他们没有收到回复
over the next 30 seconds,
之后的三十秒内
Marseilles tried to contact the flight crew two more times.
空管又试了两次
No answer.
还是没有答复
At 9:34 the control center tried a different frequency,
34分，空管再次尝试用不同频率联系
but again no response.
机组仍然没有答复
From 9:35 until 9:39
从35分到39分
the Marseilles control center tried to contact the flight crew multiple times over different frequencies.
马赛空管坚持多次用不同频率联系机组
An air traffic controller from the French air defense system
另一架飞机 以及一位法国防空系统的管制员
also tried as well as another aircraft
也尝试联系德翼9525
but each time
然而
no response from Germanwings flight 9525
德翼9525却一直没有回复
At 9:40 radar contact was lost
9点40分, 德翼9525的雷达信号消失了
the French air traffic controllers triggered a distress phase
法国空管启动了紧急程序
declaring that the aircraft and its occupants
宣布该飞行器及其乘员
were in imminent danger and required immediate assistance
处于迫在眉睫的危机之中并需要他人立即援助
At 9:41 am flight Germanwings 9525
41分,
crashed into the side of a mountain in the Alps.
德翼9525坠毁在了阿尔卑斯山脉的一侧
What happened?
到底发生了什么？
The crash occurred on a remote mountain.
事故发生在偏远山区
Because there was no access by road,
山上没通公路
emergency crew had to be brought in via helicopter.
救援人员不得不乘直升机前往
The plane was completely destroyed:
飞机撞的粉碎
the debris field vast but the pieces of the craft small.
碎片散步的区域很大, 而碎片本身却很小
The cockpit voice and flight recorder were found in the same week
驾驶舱语音记录器和飞行数据记录仪在同一周被发现
although they were both severely damaged.
不过它们也被摔的惨烈
When flight investigators stitched together the data
当调查员整合完毕数据
a story of intentional action formed.
The plane was hijacked,
飞机被劫持了
but not by terrorists.
只不过不是被恐怖分子劫持的
Let's go back.
我们来回顾一下
After the aircraft leveled off at its cruise altitude,
9点半, 飞机离开巡航高度后
the captain left the cockpit to go to the bathroom at 9:30
机长离开驾驶舱去了厕所
While he was in the bathroom,
他在厕所里时
the plane was almost immediately set
飞机立刻被设置了
for a different altitude in the cockpit
一个不同的高度
At 9:34, the captain came back and requested
access, but he got none.
34分, 机长上完厕所回来
The door was locked.
但他被锁在了驾驶舱门外
As he stood in front of that cockpit door
站在舱门前
the captain began to understand.
机长明白了
The co-pilot had hijacked the plane
副机长劫持了这架飞机
and he had no way of getting in.
而他没法进入驾驶舱
After 2001,
911事件后
cockpits were changed in order to protect those flying the plane from potential hijackers
飞机驾驶舱被改装以防止可能的劫机发生
To enter the cockpit,
机组成员想进入驾驶舱
a crew member has to call the cockpit on the intercom
就必须按键盘上的井号
and press the pound key on a keypad,
用对讲系统呼叫驾驶舱
which buzzes the cockpit.
让驾驶舱里的人听到嗡嗡声
At that moment the pilot can switch the door control
这之后飞行员可以控制舱门
from norm to unlock,
将其切换到解锁状态
and the crew member can enter.
随后机组成员便可进门
The crew is also given emergency codes
机组也有应急密码
which they can use if there are concerns for those in the cockpit.
可在驾驶舱内人员出问题时使用
in that case the crew member will use the emergency code on the keypad
机组可以在键盘上输入应急密码
triggering a 30 second timer
30秒后,
and the cockpit door will open for 5 seconds
舱门就会打开5秒钟
however there are situations where those in the cockpit
然而, 在某种情况下
want to override the access by the crew
譬如被劫机时
like during a hijacking
驾驶舱里的人可以阻止机组成员开门
in that situation the pilots can switch the door control to lock
飞行员可以把舱门切换到锁定状态
overriding all emergency access.
阻止他人用应急密码开门
and it's that mechanism
德翼9525的副机长
that the co-pilot used
正是使用了这个机制
to permanently lock access to the cockpit
锁定了驾驶舱门
while the plane began to descend.
飞机开始下降时
The captain was locked out of the cockpit
机长被锁在了外边
without any control.
无法操控飞机
At 9:39 the cockpit voice recorder
39分时,
picked up violent blows on the cockpit door.
语音记录器录下了舱门上传来的猛烈撞击声
The captain had repeatedly tried breaking in to gain access
机长尝试破门
but the cockpit door was reinforced.
但舱门为反武装劫机而设计
Made to withstand armed hijackers
十分坚固
the captain stood little chance.
机长胜算微渺
In the last minutes
在最后的几分钟里
the passengers crew and Captain
机组与乘客
all knew that the plane was going down.
都了发现飞机正在坠毁
No one survived the crash.
机上144位乘客
144 passengers
4位乘务员
four cabin crew
机长及副机长
and the captain and co-pilot died.
无人幸存
Amongst the passengers was an entire school class
乘客中, 有一整个班的孩子
returning from a field trip to Spain.
在西班牙郊游完毕正返校
The captain Patrick Sondenheimer
机长帕特里克·桑德海默*
was a 34 year old father of two.
时年34, 膝下二儿
In the aftermath his wife set up a foundation in his name
事后, 机长的妻子以他的名义设立了一家基金会
intended to help children and young people handle grief and crisis.
来帮助儿童及年轻人应对危机与悲伤
He had thousands of total flight hours
机长有数千小时的飞行经验
and his last moments were dedicated to trying to save the plane and passengers.
直到最后一刻, 他还在力图挽救乘客与飞机
The co-pilot was 27 years old
副机长时年27
and from a young age he was passionate about flying.
从小他就热衷于飞行
His bedroom had posters of Airbus Boeing and Lufthansa
他的卧室里贴着波音、空客与汉莎航空的海报
and he'd become an expert glider pilot as a child.
他小时候就精通于滑翔机驾驶
He joined Lufthansa's Flight Academy straight out of school,
他一毕业就加入了汉莎航空的飞行学院
but only a few months into the program
但仅仅几个月后
he stopped.
他就被停飞了
He was suffering from a deep depressive episode
他正经历着一次严重的抑郁症发作
treated with antidepressants
同时在服用抗抑郁药物
and spent multiple months in the care of a psychiatrist.
并接受了长达数月的治疗
Eventually he received a medical recommendation
最终他收到了一份医疗建议
declaring that he was in remission.
宣布他已处于缓解期
After a few months
数月后
his student pilot license and fit to fly medical certificate were restored,
他的学生飞行员执照与适航医疗证明被恢复
but if he needed any more psychiatric treatment
不过如果仍需要进一步的心理治疗
he'd be grounded from flying.
他就会被停飞
But he continued with his training
但他继续进行训练
until he ran into a problem.
直到撞上南墙
While filling out a document required by the U.S Federal Aviation Administration
在填写一份由美国联邦航空管理局(FAA)要求的文件,
to fly at an Arizona based Lufthansa operated flight school
以在亚利桑那州的一家汉莎航空旗下航校飞行时
he said that he had never been diagnosed
他说他从未被诊断
with any mental disorders.
患有任何精神疾病
This was a lie
这是个谎言
and he got caught.
而他被揭穿了
Lying on an FAA application can lead to a jail offense
在FAA申请中造假可能构成刑事犯罪
or the end of a flying career,
也可能终结他的飞行生涯
but the FAA gave him a second chance.
但FAA给了他第二次机会
He admitted to depression
他承认他患有抑郁症
and was accepted to go to Arizona.
In 2013 he joined Germanwings
a low-budget Airline owned by Lufthansa.
And a year later his depression returned.
He thought he was going blind
visiting ophthalmologists and neurologists multiple times per week
because he was seeing stars, halos, flashes of light, streaks, and flying insects.
But the doctor's scans didn't find much.
He was diagnosed with hypochondriacal disorder
as well as emergent psychosis from his family doctor.
And that doctor urged him to go to a psychiatric clinic,
but he do no such thing.
Instead in January of 2015
he returned to the psychiatrist
that had helped him in the first place.
He received Psychotherapy
and went on heavy antidepressants
while continuing to work and fly.
From February to March
he received multiple sick notes from multiple doctors.
He wasn't alright and he wanted something to change.
Four days before the crash
he turned to his computer to understand the locking mechanism
on the Airbus A320 cockpit door.
On his outbound flight from Dusseldorf to Barcelona
he tested the descent settings for a moment
while Sondenheimer was outside the cockpit.
On the return flight
he used it to bring down the plane.
How could this have happened?
Pilots are required to do Health screenings and annual
checkups,
but mental health is easier overlooked than physical.
Since Pilots operate under an honor system
they're expected to self-evaluate their health.
And this can be an issue.
The co-pilot was declared unfit to work by his doctor,
but he decided to just not tell his employer.
But if someone like him is a risk to Public Safety
a doctor can break doctor-patient confidentiality
and report him to authorities.
So why didn't at least one of the multiple doctors
who wrote multiple sick notes
and declared him unfit to fly
think that the co-pilot may have presented a risk for public safety?
Enough of a risk
that he couldn't be trusted to report himself?
We don't know.
The doctors may have believed the co-pilot was a risk to himself
but not to others.
Being depressed does not make you a killer.
Or maybe the doctors were just scared.
Breaking doctor-patient confidentiality does not come without risks.
It's even possible cultural factors could have played a role.
Privacy and data protection are valued really highly in Germany.
But trying to understand why doctor patient confidentiality wasn't broken
is a dilemma an issue best left to healthcare professionals and ethics professors.
And unfortunately we're YouTubers.
So we encourage you to read more about it in these articles.
Nonetheless when you're watching this today
it's important to understand that this type of incident
is incredibly unlikely.
In the aftermath the European Aviation safety agency
proposed multiple safety regulations.
Psychological screening for pilots increased
and multiple Airlines adopted a two-person in the cockpit at all-time rule
although Lufthansa has recently phased this out.
In 2015 Germanwings was rebranded to Eurowings.
The decision was made prior to the crash.
In the end Lufthansa compensated the families of the victims
but there are questions about whether it was enough.
The families have faced losses that no money can heal.
Hopefully you enjoyed this video, it was insanely hard to make.
We love animation and deep research
but it's expensive.
That's why we have sponsors on this channel.
By the way a lot of our animation in particular
actually has a lot to do with math,
be it geometry or linear algebra for specific shaders
or code for scripted and procedural animation.
Both can be exciting and fascinating
especially if taught in a playful manner.
That's where Brilliant comes in.
It gives you skills that can be applied to everything literally,
be it basic logic artificial intelligence data science or physics.
But it gives it to you in a way that isn't earth-shatteringly boring.
To try everything brilliant has to offer free for a full 30 days
visit brilliant.org/fern or click on the link in the description.
The first 200 of you will get 20 off of Brilliant's annual premium subscription.
You always have your phone on you, which means Brilliant always gives you access to learn math and science anywhere
even if it's only for a few minutes each day.
You can improve your skills while in a tram, walking
or while your significant other is trying to connect with you.
We personally love the app.
There's something incredibly satisfying
about really getting something
about solving puzzle or logic problem.
Why don't you give it a try.